This has been the most game-changing
thing that I have done to my trading in
a long time. TradingView just released a
brand new feature which allows you to
connect TradingView to Claude for the
first time ever, and it's unlocked so
many insane possibilities I'm going to
show you today. I've been playing around
with this for the last few weeks, and
today I'm going to show you how to set
it up, how to get the most out of Claude
and TradingView, and why if you
configure this correctly, this is
probably the closest thing that a retail
trader can get to a professional trading
desk. I just asked Claude to analyze the
chart and draw resistance and support
zones and help me identify my next move
in the market. And as you can see, it's
now populated my chart with the
resistance zone that could potentially
be a short or a sell setup with the
support zone that could potentially be a
buy zone and all of the key zones that I
need to be aware of, the swing low, the
weekly low, the local high, and the last
high. And on the left-hand side here,
it's paired the technical analysis with
some suggestions. It thinks that it's
not wise to enter here, and I should
wait for a long setup around the green
zone that it detailed between 71,000 and
71,800.
But this is just the tip of the iceberg.
Let me explain why Claude plus
TradingView is a game-changer. The
problem is before the TradingView MCP
released, if you wanted an AI to analyze
your charts, you would literally have to
go in, screenshot the chart, and send it
into an AI chat. And as you can imagine,
this isn't very effective as A, by the
time you would send it to a chat,
oftentimes the price had materially
changed, and B, when the AI is reading a
photo, it's having to identify pixels.
Whereas, if it's connected directly to
TradingView, it has the live data, and
it doesn't have to read the photo,
meaning it makes less mistakes. Before,
unless you gave Claude the data, it
didn't have the data. Whereas now, it
can automatically scan your watchlist,
read your charts, and actually chart on
your behalf. And that's just the tip of
the iceberg. Later in the video, I'm
going to show you how you can even use
Claude code to backtest strategies,
exemplify them on your chart, and be
your true trading assistant. I truly
believe if you set this up now, you're
going to have a huge leg up on the rest
of the market because we know that
Claude is only getting smarter. We have
Opus 4.7 launching very, very soon,
which is only going to make the model
even better. So, the sooner you can
connect this and start playing around
with it, the sooner you are going to
unlock the benefits for your trading.
Now, you don't need to know what an MCP
is to use this, but essentially what is
happening is TradingView Desktop is
feeding the live data through Chrome
DevTools protocol, streaming into an MCP
server, which is now available for the
first time. Claude then reads that data
and it's able to give you an answer or
respond to your prompt based on this
data. So, essentially, the MCP is now
the bridge between the data that used to
live on TradingView, the indicators, the
drawings, the setups, the price changes,
etc., that you previously had to
manually feed into Claude. Now, that is
all happening in real time, running 100%
locally on your machine. So, to get this
set up, you need four things. Firstly,
you need Claude installed on your
computer. You can use Claude Code
through the desktop app, as you can see
on the left of screen here. The next
thing you'll need is to download the
desktop app of TradingView. The Chrome
application is not going to work. You
need to download the desktop app in
order to link Claude to TradingView. The
next thing you'll need is to install a
local node. However, I've developed a
prompt, which I'll be giving to you for
free, which you can just copy and paste
into Claude Code, and it'll save all
these setup headaches that you may have
had if you tried to do it yourself. And
then, of course, you also need an active
TradingView subscription. So, what
you're going to do is you're going to go
into Claude Code. Remember, you'll need
to connect Claude Code to a local
folder. Just create a folder on your
desktop and connect it. Down the track,
I'm going to be showing you how you can
actually import your memory to make this
proper trading assistant. So,
essentially, you can put in your data in
terms of how you trade, what your
trading style is, what tokens you look
at, what your parameters are, and then
every time Claude Code analyzes a
strategy for you, it can be based on
your instructions and requirements, but
that is something we will build on in
future videos, so make sure you're
subscribing for that. I'm going to paste
in my full prompt here. The prompt will
be available for free using the link in
the description. All you need to do is
sign up, put in your email, and you
unlock the Instagram community, join,
it's free, and the pinned message will
contain the Google Drive with all of the
resources including this prompt from
today's video. So, what you want to do
is you want to copy and paste the full
prompt into Claude. Then it's going to
automatically start configuring the MCP,
downloading everything that you need to
download, and it's going to link it to
your TradingView desktop application.
You want to just go through and click
always allow on these messages. You will
get a few pop-ups in the beginning.
There are some workarounds that you can
actually do to decrease the amount of
manual approvals. If you go into your
Claude settings, and you get rid of the
permission toggle, this comes with extra
risks, but if you're willing to do it,
it can make this process a little bit
more seamless. The other thing you can
do is you can actually control this
remotely. There are two options. One
through Claude Dispatch, which enables
you to access Claude Code from a mobile
device. So, you could literally be
walking down the street on your phone
and analyzing TradingView, which is
pretty cool. Or for the more advanced
users, something that I've been doing,
which has been an absolute game-changer
for my trading and portfolio management,
is actually set up open Claude, so you
can control Claude Code through Telegram
and make it your 24/7 research
assistant. So, I have it sending me
automatic market briefs every day,
scanning my portfolio every day,
suggesting trades. And right now I'm in
the midst of a $20,000 trading challenge
where AI is actually trading for me with
my parameters. So, I'm filming that
right now. I can't wait to put the video
out. Make sure you subscribe because I'm
going to teach you guys on this channel
how to go step by step through your AI
journey. So, we're starting with this
tutorial, we're going to get you set up,
and then we're going to go deeper and
deeper and deeper cuz over the last few
weeks, I've been going so deep down the
AI rabbit hole, and I I believe this is
the future of trading. So, the quicker
you can embrace it, the quicker you can
get an edge over the rest of the market
and uh I think it's going to unlock some
crazy productivity for you guys. So, you
can see here on the left now it's fully
set up. It might prompt you to restart
your TradingView, but just follow the
steps and if you ever have any
questions, of course, you can just ask
Claude. But, I developed that prompt to
make it easy for you guys so you don't
have to do what I had to do in the early
days, which is basically going into the
GitHub, downloading the MCP, copying in
a bunch of manual prompts. It was
annoying. So, I upgraded with the prompt
I'm giving you guys in today's video.
Once again, link in the description for
that. So, now that we're in and things
are working, let me give you some live
demonstrations of what this can actually
do and some use cases for how you can
implement this into your trading. So,
right now I'm on the Ethereum chart and
I'm going to ask analyze this ETH chart
and give me the best long and short
opportunities right now. If you find
good setups, ask me whether I want you
to draw them on the chart. So, as you
can see here, it's marked out the key
pivot zones. So, as you can see, we have
the lows here. That's also how I would
have drawn it. You have the mid-range
pivot point, which also lines up with
the Bitcoin chart and then you have the
range highs. Pretty accurate, in my
opinion. And then on the left-hand side,
it's established some potential trading
opportunities. Now, obviously, you don't
just want to copy Claude. You want to
give it your own strategy and maybe use
the suggestions for your own trading.
But, the cool thing is it can actually
go back and backtest how it would have
performed following the strategy. So,
you can basically refine your own
trading strategy over time. And it's not
just lines on the chart. It's literally
anything on TradingView. Remember, this
is literally making your TradingView
autonomous. It's enabling you to do
things on TradingView through Claude
instead of having to do things yourself.
So, for example, I can ask it to add the
Stochastic RSI indicator and then I can
ask it to analyze based on the RSI its
relationship to Ethereum price action.
And as you can see, it's just pulled up
the RSI indicator. So, if you don't know
what an indicator's called or if you're
just lazy and you want Claude to do it
for you, you can literally ask it to
pull up an indicator. And then you can
ask it to actually analyze what it
means. So, this is so powerful if you're
just learning trading, right? Cuz if
you're just getting into things, you
might not necessarily know what it
means. If the RSI is ticking upwards
alongside price, potentially there's a
divergence happening that you're not
aware of. This is potentially a better
assistant than going and watching
YouTube videos or doing courses because
you can literally ask, "Hey, what does
this mean? Or what could this indicate?
Or what does this mean at the given
moment in time?" And if you are
following a creator and you like how
they do things, let's say they're
analyzing Delta, you can get it to bring
up the Delta heat map on the TradingView
chart, analyze it, and help you validate
a certain entry point on the chart. So,
it's basically your trading assistant,
which I really wish I had when I learned
because I had to watch hours of YouTube
videos and make so many mistakes,
whereas now you can learn about these
things, you can learn about what certain
movements on the chart and on indicators
mean just by basically having Claude
code up next to TradingView as a tutor.
And I think where this really comes in
handy is for more complex things. For
example, if you're looking at pair
trading, relative strength trading,
because portfolio management is a whole
lot more than just buy here or sell
there. It's what the opportunity cost of
holding a certain asset is. can get it
to, for example, overlay the Solana USDT
and ETH USD T charts and tell me which
one is the better buy right now.
As you can see, it's pulled up the
Solana chart overlaid with the Ethereum
chart, and now it's analyzing. So, this
saves you having to compose things
manually. Imagine if it gets more
complex. If you wanted to compare every
single major altcoin in the top 50 and
look at relative strength on the daily,
it can now do that. Instead of you
having to manually go through and create
spaghetti charts to compare altcoins, it
now can. If you don't want to do this by
typing things in, you can download
WhisperFlow, so you can literally voice
prompt with your voice and have Claude
responding to it. And as I said, you
could even be walking down the street on
your phone on Telegram voice prompting
an agent instead of needing to do this
yourself. So, you could literally say,
"Hey, go through my entire TradingView
watchlist, tell me if any altcoins are
coming close to my alert levels, and
ping me the second they do. Or ping me
the second there's an RSI divergence at
the same time as price coming into a
level. But Because the thing about
TradingView levels is that they're
static. You've got to go onto the chart,
you've got to select an alert, and it's
static. Like if it hits that price
level, then you get an alert. Whereas
what you can do with AI is you can have
more complex alert factors, like when a
momentum indicator is crossing with a
price level. And you can go deeper by
connecting to other MCPs on Open Coral
Cloud Code when liquidity for an altcoin
decreases by 20% day on day alongside
price move, alert me on Telegram if it's
in my portfolio or if it's a major
altcoin. Like basically anything. I'm
just giving you examples off the top of
my head, but literally anything that you
want an alert on you can now develop
instead of having to do everything
manually. And I've been using this a lot
in my own portfolio. Like I've watched
this on TradingView of the coins that I
hold, and if there's a material change
to the fundamentals or if there's a
major breakdown on the chart or if
there's a breakout on the chart, I
actually get alerted to that ahead of
time. And you can actually train the AI
to give you suggestions over time. So,
hey, SOL's actually breaking down versus
Ethereum. I suggest that you rebalance
10% of your SOL into Ethereum. And if it
breaks back above this level, then you
could rotate back in. Things like that.
I mean, that stuff would have been so
helpful, especially last year and the
year before when there was insane
volatility. Like honestly, I would have
saved so much money by being quicker to
invalidate. And this is one of the
reasons why I've been going so far down
the AI rabbit hole so I can become a
better trader and play more into my
strengths and not so much into my
weaknesses because one of my weaknesses
was actually executing on invalidations
because I would either bury my head in
the sand or I would wait too long so
there'd be too much of a lag time
between what I was supposed to do and
what I was actually doing. AI completely
eliminates that because now it's all
autonomous. So, there are literally no
more excuses and it's making portfolio
management and trade management better
than ever. So, you see here even on the
left it said my answer, ETH is the
better buy right now. These are the
reasons why. So, that kind of analysis I
think is really helpful. All right, but
that's basic analysis. I want to show
you the next prompt, which is quite
cool. Build me an indicator that prints
a buy label when RSI crosses through 30
and a sell label when RSI crosses
through 70, but only when price is on
the right side of the 200 EMA. Write it
in Pine Script, inject it into
TradingView, compile it, fix any errors,
and save it to my account. AKA, what
this is doing is it's creating a custom
indicator. So, you no longer need to
create indicators yourself on Pine
Script, and you no longer have to go,
which is what I was doing for about a
year and a half, into ChatGPT, create
it, manually copy and paste into
TradingView. Now, it's creating it
inside TradingView live, and you can
backtest strategies live in TradingView
with theoretical amounts of money on
various tokens. And then this will
actually add the indicator to your
account. So, if you have a certain
indicator you like, or a trading
strategy, or let's say you have a series
of indicators that you use on a
day-to-day basis, you can create a
custom version of those indicators based
on, of course, backtested data if you
want to go down that rabbit hole. You
can see here it's literally creating it
in real time, and now you have a custom
indicator with alerts created on your
account. And you can tweak it over time
based on the efficacy of the strategy.
So, now I want to show you something
really, really cool, and this is the
next step up from this. So, everything
I've shown you so far today is what you
can do locally on your computer, which
is still something I use pretty much
every single day.
But what has taken things a step further
and made it truly autonomous is actually
connecting the MCP to Open Claw. Let me
actually get up and show you. So, right
now I have a computer, a Mac mini,
sitting right there, which is always on.
This is my 24/7 market research
assistant, which is constantly scanning
the market and is actually connected to
my TradingView, so I can prompt this on
the go 24/7. So, I can send a voice
prompt to Oscar on Telegram, and I can
say something like, "Hey Oscar, how's it
going? Could you please let me know what
the top five performers on my main
watchlist are today, and if there are
any active moves that I need to make
based on my alerts or upcoming setups
that I should be aware of?" You can see
Oscar is now sending me
a review of my watchlist. This is my
actual watchlist that I was showing you
before. You can see this one here. He's
giving me some macro context what's
happening in the market, what setups I
need to watch, and I don't actually have
any active alerts right now at Trigger
Point, and he's keeping an eye on the
75K Bitcoin level as the next key level.
Everything that I was showing you
before, I can do remotely from my phone
on Telegram. And because it's Open Claw,
it has access to that entire computer.
So, this is the next step up because
you're not just beholden to doing it
manually on Cloud Code or doing it
within the Cloud app. Open Claw
basically unlocks all the AI
infrastructure so I can have different
models running different agents scanning
the market, and then I can have Opus 4.6
reviewing, and I can prompt it all from
Telegram. So, I'm going to do a full
guide on this in the future, but I'm
going to leave it at that for now
because this is just the initial
tutorial that I wanted to make. As you
can see, I'm super passionate about this
stuff, and I've been going down a rabbit
hole, but we'll leave it at that. You
can get the prompt for free in the
description below. Just sign up using
your email, and then you can claim it.
It's inside the Instagram community
under the pinned link. And in the next
video, I'm going to show you my full
setup. I'm doing a $20,000 trading
challenge just to see what I can do with
AI, and I'm probably also going to
follow this up with a sequel, which
gives you the five exact prompts that
I've been using on TradingView. And I'm
going to be doing a bunch more AI
content, so make sure you subscribe.
Thank you very much for your time today.
I will see you in the next video. Have a
lovely rest of your day. Peace out.